<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<research_topics>
  <topic>
    <title>The Pregame Ancillae</title>
    <keywords>pregame_ancillae</keywords>
    <stat>7</stat>
    <ability>28</ability>
    <base_difficulty>7</base_difficulty>
    <tier_count>1</tier_count>
    <tiers>
      <tier>
        <successes_required>1</successes_required>
        <info_text>Beneath the three elders, prior to the disappearance, were the Ancillae. 
There were six of them who ranked above the neonates in the city and they
wielded signifgant power.  Indeed, two of the six were Tremere and three of
the six were non-Camarilla clans.  The Ancillae were:

Louis Zola - Follower of Set
Janice Weaver - Gangrel (not of McLir&apos;s line)
Francesca Giovanni - Giovanni
Gideon Darkly - Samedi
Arman Raith Paul - Tremere
Frederico Del Rey - Tremere
</info_text>
      </tier>
    </tiers>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <title>The Pregame Elders</title>
    <keywords>pregame_elders</keywords>
    <stat>7</stat>
    <ability>28</ability>
    <base_difficulty>9</base_difficulty>
    <tier_count>1</tier_count>
    <modifiers>
      <modifier>
        <type>race</type>
        <value>human</value>
        <adjustment>1</adjustment>
      </modifier>
      <modifier>
        <type>race</type>
        <value>werewolf</value>
        <adjustment>1</adjustment>
      </modifier>
      <modifier>
        <type>race</type>
        <value>vampire</value>
        <adjustment>-1</adjustment>
      </modifier>
    </modifiers>
    <tiers>
      <tier>
        <successes_required>1</successes_required>
        <info_text>The city was in the hands of three elders: Prince McLir of Clan Gangrel,
Dr.  Tench of Clan Nosferatu, and Amon ak Tul (also known as Old Monster)
who was a Follower of Set.  Each was at least four hundred years old and
directly or indirectly controlled much of the city.  

Though the three rarely saw eye to eye, they all had a vested interest in
the city.  Even Old Monster wanted safety in the city and was a primary
force in the defense of the city from Werewolf attacks over a hundred years
ago.  Dr.  Tench was responsible for much of the city&apos;s infrastructure and
was incredibly influential in city business.  And McLir, was of course, the
Prince of City and ruled it under Camarilla law.  
</info_text>
      </tier>
    </tiers>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <title>The Pregame Primogen Council</title>
    <keywords>primogen_council</keywords>
    <stat>7</stat>
    <ability>28</ability>
    <base_difficulty>6</base_difficulty>
    <tier_count>1</tier_count>
    <tiers>
      <tier>
        <successes_required>1</successes_required>
        <info_text>Before the disapperances, the Prince was served by a council of Primogen,
the major representatives of the Camarilla clans.  The Primogen council was
made up of: 
 
 
Brujah --&gt; Deacon Grimes
Malkavian --&gt; Marcus Talbott
Nosferatu --&gt; Mihail Bodnarescu
Toreador --&gt; Alicia Winters
Tremere --&gt; Arman Raith Paul
Ventrue --&gt; Madeline Carper
</info_text>
      </tier>
    </tiers>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <title>Clan Gangrel</title>
    <keywords>pregame_gangrel</keywords>
    <stat>7</stat>
    <ability>28</ability>
    <base_difficulty>9</base_difficulty>
    <tier_count>2</tier_count>
    <tiers>
      <tier>
        <successes_required>2</successes_required>
        <info_text>The Gangrel were the most powerful and most numerous clan in the city,
mostly due to the fact that if you included the Prince, almost half the
gangrel were of the Prince&apos;s bloodline.  (Note: No Player may start of the
McLir bloodline).  

These were the members of Clan Gangrel at one time: 
* Fang
* Janet Weaver
* Logan Reeves
* Private Hudson
* McLir
* Fizzy Fitzgerald
* Marigold
* Nikola Sleat
</info_text>
      </tier>
      <tier>
        <successes_required>1</successes_required>
        <info_text>The Gangrel were the most powerful and most numerous clan in the city,
mostly due to the fact that if you included the Prince, almost half the
gangrel were of the Prince&apos;s bloodline.  (Note: No Player may start of the
McLir bloodline).  
</info_text>
      </tier>
    </tiers>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <title>Vampire Lore</title>
    <keywords>vampire lord kindred</keywords>
    <stat>7</stat>
    <ability>0</ability>
    <base_difficulty>6</base_difficulty>
    <tier_count>3</tier_count>
    <failure_text>Your research into vampires turns up some interesting develops. 
Apparently vampires are not supernatural creatures, but homo sapiens with a
mutant gene called the solarus imperius gene.  It&apos;s what gives them their
unique vulnerability to sunlight but they are certainly not supernatural as
most believe.  
</failure_text>
    <modifiers>
      <modifier>
        <type>clan</type>
        <value>tremere</value>
        <adjustment>-1</adjustment>
      </modifier>
    </modifiers>
    <tiers>
      <tier>
        <successes_required>1</successes_required>
        <info_text>Vampires are undead creatures that drink blood.</info_text>
      </tier>
      <tier>
        <successes_required>2</successes_required>
        <info_text>Vampires are organized into clans, each with unique powers and flaws.</info_text>
      </tier>
      <tier>
        <successes_required>3</successes_required>
        <info_text>The Camarilla is the largest vampire sect, enforcing the Masquerade.  
 
This is more text.
</info_text>
      </tier>
    </tiers>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <title>Pregame History of Bal Harbor</title>
    <keywords>city_history</keywords>
    <stat>7</stat>
    <ability>0</ability>
    <base_difficulty>6</base_difficulty>
    <tier_count>1</tier_count>
    <tiers>
      <tier>
        <successes_required>1</successes_required>
        <info_text>The City had been ruled by Camarilla Kindred since it&apos;s inception. 
Originally, the city was &apos;colonized&apos; by three elders McLir, Amon ak Tul, and
Dr.  Tench.  They setup the city, and with the exception of McLir, retired
from active Kindred politics.  McLir became the Prince of the City and ruled
under Camarilla law.  

McLir was served by a Primogen Council, two harpies, and a sheriff.  The
city&apos;s financial resources were &apos;managed&apos; by the Giovanni, with assistance
from Dr.  Tench.  In essence, the city was ruled by the Elders and then the
Ancillae.  Every other Kindred in the city was a neonate, and many would
say, a pawn of the Elders.  
 
The Elders also drove out the Werewolves from the area a long time ago and
no one has seen hide nor hair of them since.
</info_text>
      </tier>
    </tiers>
  </topic>
</research_topics>
